Guide to the Annie Lois Newkirk Blakely Papers, 1870-1988
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Annie Lois Newkirk Blakely papers 1870-1988
Blakely, Annie Lois Newkirk, 1891-1984
7.2 linear feet Extent: 4,700 Items
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
blakely
Language: English.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Annie Lois Newkirk Blakely Papers (1870-1988) were donated to the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library in 1991.
Biographical Note
1891, Nov. 11 Born in Wilmington, N.C.
ca. 1910 Attended Women's College, University of North Carolina (Greensboro, N.C.)
1918-1922 Served as Nurse, U.S. Army Nurse Corps, Greenville S.C.
1922, Aug. 24 Married Ralph Royd Blakely in Clinton, S.C.
1923, Sept. 3 Daughter, Florence Ella Blakely, born
1926, May 18 Daughter, Ann Newkirk Blakely, born
1984, Oct. 16 Died in Durham, N.C.
Collection Overview
The Annie Lois Newkirk Blakely Papers, 1870-1988, contain chiefly correspondence and diaries but also include legal papers, pictures, and clippings. The collection primarily documents the life of Blakely as a Clinton, S.C. housewife and mother, and of her children, Florence Ella Blakely and Ann Newkirk Blakely McLeod. Much of the Correspondence Series consists of personal letters by family members and friends written to Annie Lois Newkirk Blakely, her husband Ralph Royd Blakely, daughters Florence Ella Blakely (a Duke University librarian), and Ann Newkirk Blakely McLeod. A large portion of this series contain correspondence (1921-1978) between Annie and Ralph Blakely before they were married. Although the Diaries Series (1927-1978) contains primarily the journals of Annie Lois Newkirk Blakely, other family members Florence Ella Blakely and Inez Robertson Blakely, are also included. The Pictures Series contains family photographs of vacations, holidays, and weddings. The Legal Papers Series primarily contains banking and investment correspondence, as well as personal legal Items, such as Annie Blakely's discharge papers from the U.S. Army and Ralph Blakely's discharge papers from the U.S. Navy after World War I. The Miscellaneous Series includes War Ration Books from the 1940s and photocopied newspaper clippings that pertain to the Blakely and Newkirk families.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Newkirk family; Blakely family; Housewives -- South Carolina; Mothers and daughters -- South Carolina; Women -- South Carolina -- Correspondence; Diaries -- Women
Contents of Collection
- Correspondence, 1921-1988, undated
  Includes personal letters of Annie Lois Newkirk Blakely, Florence Ella Blakely, Ralph Blakely, Ann Newkirk and letters addressed to both Mr. and Mrs. Blakely. Correspondence between Annie Lois and Ralph Blakely while dating during the early 1920s is most prominent. Arranged by recipient in chronological order by day, month and year.
  - Blakely, Annie Lois Newkirk, 1921-1922, Aug., (6 folders) (Box 1)
  - Blakely, Annie Lois Newkirk, 1923-1969, (7 folders) (Box 2)
  - Blakely, Annie Lois Newkirk, 1970, undated, (2 folders) (Box 3)
  - Blakely, Florence Ella, 1934-1972, (7 folders)
  - Blakely, Florence Ella, 1972-1983, (7 folders) (Box 4)
  - Blakely, Florence Ella, 1984, Feb. 1-1988, undated, (7 folders) (Box 5)
  - Blakely, Ralph,. 1918-1922, Apr. 17, (8 folders) (Box 6)
  - Blakely, Ralph, 1922, Apr. 18-1958, undated, (5 folders) (Box 7)
  - Blakely, Mr. and Mrs., 1942-1954, (2 folders)
  - Blakely, Mr. and Mrs., 1946-1948, (6 folders) (Box 8)
  - Blakely, Mr. and Mrs., 1949-1955, (9 folders) (Box 9)
  - Blakely, Mr. and Mrs., 1956-1959, Aug., (7 folders) (Box 10)
  - Blakely, Mr. and Mrs., 1959, Sept.-1966, undated, (5 folders) (Box 11)
  - Blakely, Ann Newkirk, 1940-1969, undated
  - Other, 1923-1974, undated
- Diaries, 1927-1978.
  Primarily contains diaries of Annie Lois Blakely and other family members including Florence Ella Blakely and Inez Robertson Blakely. Annie Lois Blakely's diaries disclose information recording her day to day activities. Entries vary from detailed writings to a few short sentences. Arranged in chronological order.
  - Blakely, Annie Lois Newkirk, 1927-1949, (4 folders) (Box 12)
  - Blakely, Annie Lois Newkirk, 1950-1961, (5 folders) (Box 13)
  - Blakely, Annie Lois Newkirk, 1962-1968, (4 folders) (Box 14)
  - Blakely, Annie Lois Newkirk, 1969-1974, (4 folders) (Box 15)
  - Blakely, Annie Lois Newkirk, 1975-1978, (3 folders) (Box 16)
  - Other, 1933-1943, (2 folders)
- Legal Papers, 1942-1960, undated
  Contains papers regarding the legal affairs of Annie and Ralph Blakely and their children. Includes papers including bank and investments statements. Also contains War Ration Books from World War II and information regarding Annie's reserve and active service in the U.S. Army Nurse Corps, 1918-1922. Contains discharge of Yeoman 1st-Class Ralph Blakely, U.S.S. Hartford, U.S. Navy, 1919.
  - Blakely, Ann Newkirk, 1942-1985, undated, (2 folders) (Box 17)
  - Blakely, Annie Lois Newkirk, 1918-1985, undated
  - Blakely, Florence Ella, 1942-1984
  - Blakely, Ralph, 1911-1958, undated, (2 folders)
  - Miscellaneous, 1917-1960, undated
- Pictures Series,1870's-1984, undated
  Includes family, vacation, and wedding photographs. Arranged chronologically.
  - ca. 1870's-1984, (2 folders)
  - 1968-1984
  - undated (Box 18)
  - Negatives, undated
- Clippings, 1935-1904, undated
  Includes acid-free photocopies and originals of newspaper clippings.
  - 1935-1990, undated
- Miscellaneous, 1919-1984, undated
  Includes miscellaneous items including an address book, calendar, and other items. Arranged in chronological order.
  - 1919-1984, undated, (4 folders)
- Oversize Materials
  - Pictures, 1870's-1968 (Oversize-box 15)